A Guide to the Papers of Collins Denny 1872-1943
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Collins Denny Correspondence
  - 1923- 1943
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Po 1922- 1943 (Box-folder 50:26)
    - S. L. Prince to Collins Denny 1928 July 20-1928 October 29 (Box-folder 51:1)
    - C. K. Proctor to Collins Denny 1925 March 3-1927 November 28 (Box-folder 51:2)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence 1922- 1943 (Box-folder 51:3)
      Re: Prohibition, 1907-1933
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Pr-Py 1922-1934 (Box-folder 51:4)
    - Collins Denny Sr. Outgoing Correspondence 1922-1943 (Box-folder 51:5)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Q 1923- 1943 (Box-folder 51:6)
    - Collins Denny Sr. Outgoing Correspondence 1922- 1943 (Box-folder 51:7)
    - J. F. Rawls to Collins Denny 1927 April 4-1929 April 9 (Box-folder 51:8)
    - Roberta Ray to Collins Denny 1924 March 10-1925 November 10 (Box-folder 51:9)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Ra 1923- 1943 (Box-folder 51:10)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Re's 1922-1934 (Box-folder 51:11)
    - R. E. Riddick to Collins Denny 1928 January 11-1929 June 5 (Box-folder 51:12)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Ri 1923- 1943 (Box-folder 51:13)
    - A. H. Robinson Collins Denny 1928 January 3-1929 August 26 (Box-folder 51:14)
    - J. M. Rogers to Collins Denny 1924 May 12-1938 March 18 (Box-folder 51:15)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Ro's 1923- 1943 (Box-folder 51:16)
    - Robert Ruff to Collins Denny 1924 February 4-1929 January 23 (Box-folder 51:17)
    - J. W. Rustin to Collins Denny 1928 September 12-1930 March 26 (Box-folder 51:18)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Ru-Ry 1923- 1943 (Box-folder 51:19)
    - Collins Denny Sr. Outgoing Correspondence 1922-1943 (Box-folder 51:20)
    - M. A. Stevenson to Collins Denny 1937 June 12-1938 January 27 (Box-folder 51:21)
    - Charles J. Steward to Collins Denny 1938 January 19-1938 October 5 (Box-folder 51:22)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; S's 1923-1943 (Box-folder 51:23)
    - Collins Denny Sr. Outgoing Correspondence 1922- 1943 (Box-folder 51:24)
    - Luther Todd to Collins Denny 1923 June 25-1923 July 6 (Box-folder 52:1)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence 1922- 1934 (Box-folder 52:2)
      re: Free Transportation of the Clergy
    - R. E. Travis to Collins Denny 1925 February 25-1928 September 20 (Box-folder 52:3)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; T-V 1923-1943 (Box-folder 52:4)
    - Collins Denny Sr. Outgoing Correspondence; T's 1922-1943 (Box-folder 52:5)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence 1922-1934 (Box-folder 52:6)
    - Allen H. Whisner to Collins Denny 1922 September 11-1923 August 22 (Box-folder 52:7)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; W-Z 1923- 1943 (Box-folder 52:8)
    - Collins Denny Sr. Outgoing Correspondence; W-Y 1922-1943 (Box-folder 52:9)
    - Collins Denny Sr. Outgoing Correspondence; Miscellaneous 1922- 1943 (Box-folder 52:10)
    - Petitions to Collins Denny 1923- 1928 (Box-folder 52:11)
    - Petitions and Resolutions to Collins Denny n.d. (Box-folder 52:12)
    - Collins Denny Correspondence; Miscellaneous n.d. (Box-folder 52:13)
  - By States
    - Official Correspondence 1905 (Box-folder 53:1)
      "To all my friends in Lewisburg, West Virginia"
    - Official Correspondence 1906 (Box-folder 53:2)
      re: Methodist Episcopal Church, South Conference
    - Official Correspondence 1898- 1908 (Box-folder 53:3)
      re: Book Committee and Publishing House case
    - Official Correspondence 1900-1908 (Box-folder 53:4)
      re: Publishing House
    - Official Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 53:5)
      re: Publishing House in China, Book Committee
    - Official Correspondence to City of Nashville 1904 (Box-folder 53:6)
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1933 (Box-folder 53:7)
      re: Book Agents and Publishing House
    - Official Correspondence 1912- 1933 (Box-folder 53:8)
      re: N. R. A. and Publishing House
    - Official Correspondence 1909- 1910 (Box-folder 53:9)
      re: Rules for General Conference
    - Officials Correspondence 1877- 1910 (Box-folder 53:10)
      re: Methodist books in Methodist Discipline
    - Official Correspondence 1911 (Box-folder 53:11)
      re: Fourth Ecumenical Methodist Conference
    - Official Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 53:12)
      re: Bible of 1911
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1922 (Box-folder 53:13)
      re: Proposed move to St. Louis
    - Official Correspondence 1911-1913 (Box-folder 53:14)
      re: Barnes Hospital
    - Official Correspondence 1911-1913 (Box-folder 54:1)
    - Official Correspondence 1913 (Box-folder 54:2)
      re: Case of W. H. H. Joyce of Baltimore Conference
    - Official Miscellaneous Correspondence to College of Bishops 1913-1914 (Box-folder 54:3)
    - Official Correspondence 1914 (Box-folder 54:4)
      re: Votes on change of name of church
    - Official Correspondence 1912-1915 (Box-folder 54:5)
      re: Meetings of College of Bishops
    - Resolutions of the College of Bishops of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South 1914 May 12 (Box-folder 54:6)
    - Official Correspondence 1914 (Box-folder 54:7)
      re: Woman's Laity League and Laity Rights
    - Minutes of Spring Meeting of the College of Bishops 1918 (Box-folder 54:8)
    - Official Correspondence 1914 & 1926 (Box-folder 54:9)
      re: Requests on assignments to College of Bishops
    - Official Correspondence 1920 (Box-folder 54:10)
      re: Decision of law given at Kentucky Conference
    - Official Correspondence 1921 (Box-folder 54:11)
      re: Ashbury Tablet
    - Official Correspondence 1911-1931 (Box-folder 54:12)
      re: Minutes of College of Bishops and Church Boards
    - "To th Committee on Appeals of the Methodist Church... " 1922 May 8 (Box-folder 54:13)
    - Official Correspondence 1924 (Box-folder 54:14)
      re: Minority report of Bishops on Unification; appeal to the Offical Records
    - Official Correspondence 1925 (Box-folder 54:15)
      re: Bishop James Cannon and Unification
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1924 (Box-folder 54:16)
      re: Methodist Church Unification
    - Official Correspondence 1924- 1926 (Box-folder 54:17)
      re: Unification
    - Official Miscellaneous Correspondence 1925 (Box-folder 54:18)
    - Official Correspondence 1922- 1926 (Box-folder 55:1)
    - Official Correspondence 1923- 1925 (Box-folder 55:2)
    - Official Miscellaneous Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 55:3)
    - Official Miscellaneous Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 55:4)
    - Official Correspondence [1925?] (Box-folder 55:5)
      re: Carolina Conferences
    - Official Correspondence 1931- 1933 (Box-folder 55:6)
      re: Bishop Cannon Case
    - Materials 1930- 1931 (Box-folder 55:7)
    - Official Correspondence from Northern Methodists 1932 (Box-folder 55:8)
    - Official Correspondence 1933 (Box-folder 55:9)
      re: Church Law Questions
    - Official Correspondence from Baltimore Conference friends 1933 (Box-folder 55:10)
    - Official Miscellaneous Correspondence 1914- 1933 (Box-folder 55:11)
    - Official Miscellaneous Correspondence to General Conferences n.d. (Box-folder 55:12)
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1915 (Box-folder 56:1)
      re: Alabama
    - Official Correspondence 1902-1911 (Box-folder 56:2)
      re: Arkansas
    - Official Correspondence 1932 (Box-folder 56:3)
      re: California
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1932 (Box-folder 56:4)
      re: Florida
    - Offical Correspondence 1912- 1927 (Box-folder 56:5)
      re: Georgia
    - Official Correspondence 1912- 1929 (Box-folder 56:6)
      re: Kentucky
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1927 (Box-folder 56:7)
      re: Louisiana
    - Official Correspondence 1907-1927 (Box-folder 56:8)
      re: Maryland
    - Offical Correspondence 1924- 1930 (Box-folder 57:1)
      re: Maryland Conference
    - Official Correspondence 1917 & 1918 (Box-folder 57:2)
      re: Mexico Conference
    - Official Correspondence 1911-1933 (Box-folder 57:3)
      re: Mississippi Conference; A-D
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1933 (Box-folder 57:4)
      re: Mississippi Conference; F-O
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1933 (Box-folder 57:5)
      re: Mississippi Conference: P-Z
    - Official Correspondence 1910- 1931 (Box-folder 57:6)
      re: Missouri Conference
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1933 (Box-folder 57:7)
    - Official Correspondence 1911- 1933 (Box-folder 57:8)
    - Official Correspondence 1910- 1926 (Box-folder 58:1)
    - Official Correspondence 1928- 1931 (Box-folder 58:2)
    - Official Correspondence 1923- 1925 (Box-folder 58:3)
      re: North Carolina
    - Official Correspondence 1923-1925 (Box-folder 58:4)
    - Official Correspondence 1923- 1925 (Box-folder 58:5)
    - Official Miscellaneous Correspondence 1910- 1932 (Box-folder 58:6)
    - Official Correspondence 1910- 1912 (Box-folder 58:7)
      re: Oklahoma
    - Official Correspondence 1910- 1912 (Box-folder 59:1)
    - Official Correspondence 1910- 1912 (Box-folder 59:2)
    - Official Correspondence 1910- 1912 (Box-folder 59:3)
    - Official Correspondence 1917- 1933 (Box-folder 59:4)
      re: South Carolina
    - Official Correspondence 1917- 1933 (Box-folder 59:5)
    - Official Correspondence 1899- 1932 (Box-folder 60:1)
      re: Tennessee
    - Official Correspondence 1912- 1933 (Box-folder 60:2)
      re: Texas
    - Official Correspondence 1902- 1932 (Box-folder 60:3)
      re: Virginia
    - Official Correspondence 1915- 1930 (Box-folder 60:4)
    - Official Correspondence 1926- 1929 (Box-folder 60:5)
    - Official Correspondence 1912- 1932 (Box-folder 60:6)
      re: West Virginia
- Family Correspondence
  - Joseph S. Collins to John Collins 1835 (Box-folder 61:1)
  - Letters to John A. Collins 1838- 1852 (Box-folder 61:2)
  - J. S. Carson to Joseph S. Collins 1851 August 12 (Box-folder 61:3)
  - G. W. Z. Black to W. R. Denny 1899 March 31-1903 January 10 (Box-folder 61:4)
  - W. R. Denny to Collins Denny 1866 July 23-1876 September 6 (Box-folder 61:5)
  - W. R. Denny to Collins Denny 1877 January 5-1890 November 21 (Box-folder 61:6)
  - W. R. Denny to Collins Denny 1891 February 8-1893 December 27 (Box-folder 61:7)
  - W. R. Denny to Collins Denny 1894 February 9-1896 October 16 (Box-folder 61:8)
  - W. R. Denny to Collins Denny 1897 January 20-1902 September 13 (Box-folder 61:9)
  - Collins Denny to W. R. Denny 1900 July 2-1900 July 3 (Box-folder 61:10)
  - Mary D. Campbell to W. R. Denny 1900 March 4-1901 February 4 (Box-folder 61:11)
  - Jas. W. Denny to W. R. Denny 1893 December 22-1904 February 6 (Box-folder 61:12)
  - Mary Denny to W. R. Denny 1895 March 27-1900 February 10 (Box-folder 61:13)
  - W. R. Denny to Lucy C. Denny 1901 September 17 (Box-folder 61:14)
  - W. R. Denny to Lucy and Edith Denny 1897 August 3 (Box-folder 61:15)
  - W. R. Denny Correspondence 1893 April 27-1901 December 12 (Box-folder 61:16)
  - Letter to Margaret Collins Denny from her mother 1901 March 6-1901 March 15 (Box-folder 61:17)
  - Family Correspondence 1891-1897 (Box-folder 61:18)
    W. R. Denny, A. S. Denny and others re: Denny Bros., San Marcos, Texas
  - J. S. Denny to Collins Denny 1892 September 2-1896 December 23 (Box-folder 61:19)
  - D.E. Dudley to Jas. W. Denny [?] December 14 (Box-folder 61:20)
  - Agnes B. Collins to Collins Denny 1895 May 20-1902 January 20 (Box-folder 61:21)
  - Anna M. Chapman to Collins Denny 1892 December 10 (Box-folder 61:22)
  - Wm. A. Chapman to Collins Denny 1895 May 21 (Box-folder 61:23)
  - Margaret Ann Collins Denny to Collins Denny 1869 December 27-1879 December 23 (Box-folder 62:1)
  - Margaret Ann Collins (Mother) to Collins Denny 1880 January 13-1893 January 31 (Box-folder 62:2)
  - Collins Denny to Margaret Ann Collins Denny 1910 November 16 & n.d. (Box-folder 62:3)
  - James W. Denny to Collins Denny 1892 December 21-1912 December 17 (Box-folder 62:4)
  - Carrie Collins to Collins Denny 1872 September 29-1890 February 23 (Box-folder 62:5)
  - John H. Denny to Collins Denny 1874 April 11-1897 December 29 (Box-folder 62:6)
  - Margaret Ann Collins to John H. Denny n.d. (Box-folder 62:7)
  - "Ma" to Collins Denny 1892 May 20-1900 February 17 (Box-folder 62:8)
  - "Kate" to Margaret Ann Collins n.d. (Box-folder 62:9)
  - Belle Denny to Collins Denny 1886 August 28-1893 November 16 (Box-folder 62:10)
  - Collins Denny Family Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 62:11)
    re: Death of John H. Denny
  - John H. Denny to Margaret James 1899 October 11 (Box-folder 62:12)
  - John H. Denny to Mary D. Campbell 1898 April 30-1899 November 30 (Box-folder 62:13)
  - John H. Denny to Harvey Campbell 1898 October 25-1899 October 27 (Box-folder 62:14)
  - John H. Danny to W. R. Denny 1899 August 10 (Box-folder 62:15)
  - Collins Denny to Mrs. Collins Denny 1913 August 15-1922 June 12 (Box-folder 62:16)
  - Mrs. Collins Denny to Collins Denny 1910 June 18-1933 November 13 (Box-folder 62:17)
  - Collins Denny to Mary D. Campbell 1880 September 5 (Box-folder 63:1)
  - Mary D. Campbell to Collins Denny 1890 October 10-1903 March 16 (Box-folder 63:2)
  - Mary D. Campbell to Collins Denny 1904 January 25-1921 January 4 (Box-folder 63:3)
  - Mary D. Campbell to Collins Denny 1921 January 22-1934 March 4 (Box-folder 63:4)
  - Mary Denny Campbell to Collins Denny n.d. (Box-folder 63:5)
  - Mary D. Campbell to Lucy C. Denny 1890 March 23-1932 April 24 & n.d. (Box-folder 63:6)
  - Harvey J. Campbell to Collins Denny 1893 March 6-1928 July 31 (Box-folder 63:7)
  - Mary D. Campbell to Margaret D. James 1925 February 11-1926 December 8 (Box-folder 63:8)
  - Mary D. Campbell to James W. Denny 1919 May 19 (Box-folder 63:9)
  - Collins Denny to Margaret D. James 1913 October 23-1924 July 1 (Box-folder 63:10)
  - Margaret (Maggie) Denny James to Collins Denny 1875 April 27-1903 October 11 (Box-folder 63:11)
  - Margaret D. James to Collins Denny 1906 November 10-1934 March 23 & n.d. (Box-folder 63:12)
  - Margaret D. James to Lucy C. Denny 1917 April 14-1921 November 20 (Box-folder 63:13)
  - Margaret D. James to Mary D. Campbell 1920 December 31-1921 January 19 & n.d. (Box-folder 63:14)
  - Margaret D. James to Elizabeth D. Vann 1923 April 2 (Box-folder 63:15)
  - C. Pope to Margaret Denny James 1902 (Box-folder 63:16)
  - Donald James to Collins Denny 1928 December 14-1933 September 2 (Box-folder 63:17)
  - Helen James to Collins Denny 1919 February 14-1920 December 10 (Box-folder 63:18)
  - Collins Denny to Marguerite James 1930 July 4 (Box-folder 63:19)
  - Marguerite James to Collins Denny 1917 September 14-1930 October 13 (Box-folder 63:20)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Collins Denny 1907 May 28-1919 May 4 (Box-folder 64:1)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Collins Denny 1920 March 4-1929 May 6 (Box-folder 64:2)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Collins Denny 1930 February 4-1941 July 23 (Box-folder 64:3)
  - Collins Denny to Collins Denny, Jr. 1913 October 18-1937 September 7 (Box-folder 64:4)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Mrs. Collins Denny 1906 January 10-1915 November 25 & n.d. (Box-folder 64:5)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Mrs. Collins Denny 1916 February 18-1917 November 13 (Box-folder 64:6)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Mrs. Collins Denny 1918 January 5-1918 October 23 (Box-folder 64:7)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Mrs. Collins Denny 1920 April 3-1924 April 27 (Box-folder 64:8)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Edith Denny 1910 May 10-1922 May 18 (Box-folder 64:9)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Margaret Denny 1911 August 28-1916 October 5 (Box-folder 64:10)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Lucy Denny 1907 August 15-1920 December 10 & n.d. (Box-folder 64:11)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. to Elizabeth Denny 1916 September 26-1918 August 14 (Box-folder 64:12)
  - Mrs. Collins Denny to Lucy and Denny Collins, Jr. 1909 January 10 (Box-folder 64:13)
  - Carter Glass to Collins Denny, Jr. 1917 January 23-1917 January 30 (Box-folder 64:14)
  - Collins Denny, Jr. Miscellaneous Correspondence 1917-1924 & n.d. (Box-folder 64:15)
  - Margaret Denny to Collins Denny 1896 March 28-1898 July 25 (Box-folder 65:1)
  - Collins Denny to Elizabeth D. Vann 1937 August 31 (Box-folder 65:2)
  - Collins Denny to Lucy Chase Denny Wright Slosson 1913 November 11-1937 October 4 (Box-folder 65:3)
  - Edith D. White to Collins Denny 1910 June 30-1940 August 30 (Box-folder 65:4)
  - Edith Allen Denny White to Margaret Ann Collins Denny 1925 January 29 (Box-folder 65:5)
  - Collins Denny to Roscoe White 1923 February 1 (Box-folder 65:6)
  - Roscoe M. White to Collins Denny 1914 September 27-1928 July 11 (Box-folder 65:7)
  - Elizabeth Denny Vann to Collins Denny 1908 April 3-1922 December 9 & n.d. (Box-folder 65:8)
  - Elizabeth Denny Vann to Margaret Denny 1903 August 24 (Box-folder 65:9)
  - Lucy C. Denny Wright Slosson to Collins Denny 1901 August 16-1923 March 24 & n.d. (Box-folder 65:10)
  - W. C. Lowndes to Collins Denny 1897 November 26-1911 February 2 (Box-folder 65:11)
  - Lillie C. Lowndes to Collins Denny 1925 January 31 (Box-folder 65:12)
  - Andrew J. Lowndes to Collins Denny 1905 July 7 (Box-folder 65:13)
  - Wm. C. Lowndes, Jr. to Collins Denny 1909 February 9-1926 October 1 (Box-folder 65:14)
  - Elizabeth Krebs to Collins Denny 1923 April 6-1926 November 11 (Box-folder 65:15)
  - Stephen to Collins Denny 1919 February 3 & n.d. (Box-folder 65:16)
  - Denny White to Collins Denny 1931 January 5-1931 September 22 (Box-folder 65:17)
  - Lou White to Collins Denny 1940 September 3 and n.d. (Box-folder 65:18)
  - Mary Barbour to Collins Denny 1932 January 3 (Box-folder 65:19)
  - Marvin White to Collins Denny 1940 September 3 (Box-folder 65:20)
  - James L. Denny to Collins Denny 1914 November 3 and n.d. (Box-folder 65:21)
  - Collins Denny, III to Collins Denny 1941 July 25 (Box-folder 65:22)
  - Harry L. Denny to Collins Denny 1913 July 11-1926 October 18 (Box-folder 65:23)
  - J. W. Denny to Collins Denny 1911 June 16-1922 December 27 (Box-folder 65:24)
  - Collins Denny to Jos. W. Denny 1912 December 10-1913 December 11 (Box-folder 65:25)
  - Caleb S. Denny to Collins Denny 1912 November 5-1913 June 25 (Box-folder 65:26)
  - Eva Grove Kronk to Collins Denny 1917 July 25-1939 June 19 (Box-folder 65:27)
  - Linna H. Denny to Collins Denny 1892 August 22-1926 January 3 (Box-folder 65:28)
  - Jos. L. Denny to Collins Denny 1896 (Box-folder 65:29)
  - Fanny D. Fitch to Collins Denny 1898 June 29-1906 April 27 (Box-folder 65:30)
  - Fanny Denny Fitch to Joseph Denny 1896 June 22 (Box-folder 65:31)
  - Susanna C. Collins to Collins Denny 1924 November 25-1933 April 12 (Box-folder 65:32)
  - Joe Denny to Collins Denny 1917 July 17 (Box-folder 65:33)
  - R. A. Denny to Collins Denny 1914 (Box-folder 65:34)
  - "Mother May" to Edith 1940 September 5 (Box-folder 65:35)
    re: Death of Mrs. Collins Denny
  - W. C. Lowndes, Jr. to Uncle Jimmy 1920 October 6 (Box-folder 65:36)
  - Letter of Edith D. White for Collins Denny 1941 January 13 (Box-folder 65:37)
  - G. C. Denny to Collins Denny 1934 May 28 (Box-folder 65:38)
  - Correspondence to Collins Denny 1921 March 21-1932 February 2 (Box-folder 65:39)
    re: R. L. Denny--imposter
  - John C. Collins to Dr. Pierson 1888 October 20 (Box-folder 65:40)
  - Jessie D. Chappell to Margaret Ann Collins Denny 1925 February 24 (Box-folder 65:41)
  - Correspondence; fragments and letters with no identifiable signature n.d. (Box-folder 65:42)
- Collins Denny Papers: Articles and Speeches
  - "Analysis of Noah K. Davis's Elements of Deductive Logic and of his Elements of Psychology" n.d. (Box-folder 66:1)
  - Untitled manuscript n.d. (Box-folder 66:2)
    re: Influence of race and climate on the arts, politics and religion
  - Draft of speech "Should Emigration be Encouraged?" 1875 September 30 (Box-folder 66:3)
  - Confederate Memorial Address, Lewisburg West Virginia 1884 June (Box-folder 66:4)
  - "Our Japan Mission" 1886 (Box-folder 66:5)
    published letters to Bro. Boyle
  - "Corporal Dick," article in Youth's Companion1888 (Box-folder 66:6)
  - "The Principles of Style," at University of Virginia 1890 December. (Box-folder 66:7)
  - "Shakspere's Jaques-Can we respect him?" at University of Virginia 1891 March (Box-folder 66:8)
  - "Milton's Greatest Poems" at University of Virginia 1891 May 7 (Box-folder 66:9)
  - Speech, Epworth League Convention, Cleveland 1893 (Box-folder 66:10)
  - "Sunday School Lesson" in Christian Advocate1893 May & June, 13 articles (Box-folder 66:11)
  - Delivery of Medals, Dental Commencement, Vanderbilt 1893 (Box-folder 66:12)
  - Article, "The Resurrection" 1895 April (Box-folder 66:13)
  - Notes for Round Table Discussion "The Armenian Question," Nashville, Tenn. 1896 (Box-folder 66:14)
  - Article "The General Conference of 1784" 1896 January (Box-folder 66:15)
  - Drafts of "The General Conference of 1784" n.d. (Box-folder 66:16)
  - Article "Was the 'Christmas Conference' a General Conference" 1896 (Box-folder 66:17)
  - Commencement Address at Emory College 1897 (Box-folder 66:18)
  - Address, University of Nashville, "Thomas Caryle, as a man and as a writer" 1897 (Box-folder 66:19)
  - Review of T. A. Kerley's Conference Rights1898 (Box-folder 66:20)
  - Review of Townsend MacConn's The Holy Land in Geography and History1897 January (Box-folder 66:21)
  - Review of Dr. J. W. Lee's "The Romance of Palestine" 1898 March (Box-folder 66:22)
  - Speeches to General Conference 1898 (Box-folder 66:23)
  - Article, "The First Attack on the Methodist Church" 1899 February (Box-folder 66:24)
  - Comments on the Monistic Law of Production by Derivation 1899 (Box-folder 66:25)
  - Book Review, "The Land of Israel" 1900 March (Box-folder 66:26)
  - Article, "Reverend J. Hoffman Waugh, D. D." 1902 March (Box-folder 66:27)
  - Notes for Round Table Discussion, Nashville, Tenn. 1902 November (Box-folder 66:28)
  - Article and pamplet, "Some Functions of a Creed" 1906 (Box-folder 66:29)
  - [Speech?] Notes at Methodist Episcopal Church, South Conference 1906 (Box-folder 66:30)
  - Article "Athanasius, the Man and His Work: A Sketch" 1906 October (Box-folder 66:31)
  - Article (Eulogy) "Bishop A. Coke Smith" 1907 January (Box-folder 66:32)
  - Book Review, "Articles of Religion" 1907 February (Box-folder 66:33)
  - [Article] "Rev. Peter Harrison Whisner, D. D." 1907 February (Box-folder 66:34)
  - Article "Rev. Paul Whitehead, D. D." 1907 April (Box-folder 66:35)
  - Book Review "Fitchett's Wesley and His Century" 1907 May (Box-folder 67:1)
  - Sketch and Reviews of Noah K. Davis "The Story of the Nazarene in Annotated Paraphrase" 1907 (Box-folder 67:2)
  - Contribution to United Editor's Encyclopedia & Dictionary 1907 (Box-folder 67:3)
  - Article "Joshua Soule" [1907?] (Box-folder 67:4)
  - Book Review "Dr. Smith on Jersusalem" 1908 December. (Box-folder 67:5)
  - Fraternal address at Conference 1908 (Box-folder 67:6)
  - Statement for Joint Commission on Federation, between Methodist Episcopal and Methodist Episcopal Church, South 1908 November 25 (Box-folder 67:7)
  - Article "The Signs of a Son" 1909 January (Box-folder 67:8)
  - Article "Abraham Lincoln" 1909 January (Box-folder 67:9)
  - Book Review "The Cities of St. Paul" 1909 February (Box-folder 67:10)
  - Article "William Booth of the Salvation Army" 1909 April (Box-folder 67:11)
  - "A Bit of Church History" 1909 December (Box-folder 67:12)
  - Article "Episcopal Seals" 1910 January (Box-folder 67:13)
  - Book Review "Dr. Alexander's Commentary on Colossians and Ephesians" 1910 [March ?] (Box-folder 67:14)
  - Speech "Robert E. Lee: The Flower of the South" 1910 April (Box-folder 67:15)
  - Article "A New Edition of the Discipiline" 1911 January (Box-folder 67:16)
  - Speech on Unification, St. Louis, Mo. 1911 February (Box-folder 67:17)
  - Tribute to Oscar P. Fitzgerald 1911 August (Box-folder 67:18)
  - Article "Build That Church" 1912 January (Box-folder 67:19)
  - Address to Alabama Conference 1912 (Box-folder 67:20)